They Broke Every Rule.
Nine 1/2 Weeks is a drama, romance film directed by Adrian Lyne.
An erotic story about a woman, the assistant of an art gallery, who
gets involved in an impersonal affair with a man.
She barely knows about his life, only about the sex games they
play, so the relationship begins to get complicated.
John, played by Mickey Rourke.
Elizabeth, played by Kim Basinger.
Molly, played by Margaret Whitton.
Harvey, played by David Margulies.
Thea, played by Christine Baranski.
Sue, played by Karen Young.
9½ Weeks is a 1986 American erotic romantic drama film directed by
Adrian Lyne, and starring Mickey Rourke and Kim Basinger.
The film follows New York City art gallery employee Elizabeth McGraw (Basinger) who has a
brief yet intense affair with mysterious Wall Street broker John Gray (Rourke).
The screenplay by Patricia Knop, Zalman King and Sarah Kernochan is adapted from the 1978 memoir of the
same name by Austrian-American author Ingeborg Day, under the pseudonym "Elizabeth McNeill".
Principal photography was completed in August 1984, but the
film was not released until February 1986.
Considered too explicit by its American distributor Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, 9½ Weeks was heavily edited for release in
the United States, where it was a box-office bomb, grossing $6.7 million on a $17 million budget.
It also received mixed reviews at the time of its release.
However, its soundtrack sold well and the film itself became a huge success internationally in its unedited version,
particularly in Australia, Canada, France, Germany and the United Kingdom, grossing $100 million worldwide.
It has also acquired a large fanbase on video and DVD
and has developed a cult following.
The film explores themes of new york city, prostitute,
sexual obsession, fetish, eroticism.
The tone is emotional.